{"tossups": [{"question": "This author of<em> Postcards from the Edge</em> wrote multiple autobiographical works that openly discuss her positive experience with electroconvulsive therapy as treatment for bipolar disorder. This author of the memoir<em> The Princess Diarist</em> is, with her mother, the subject of<em> Bright Lights</em>, a documentary that premiered on HBO in January 2017, just weeks after their deaths. For ten points, name this mental health advocate, daughter of Debbie Reynolds, and actress who portrayed Princess Leia in the<em> Star Wars</em> films.", "answer": "Carrie<b> Fisher</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "These people discovered a \u201cland of stone slabs\u201d that might be the Torngat Mountains. These people harvested lumber from Markland and recorded finding grapes in another area. These people battled against Skraelings and found grapes during their brief settlements in Vinland and at L\u2019Anse Aux Meadows. The first European peoples to land in Canada were, for ten points, what Scandinavians, including the explorer Leif Ericsson?", "answer": "<b> Norse</b>men (or<b> Viking</b>s; accept<b> Dane</b>s or<b> Greenlander</b>s; prompt on Scandinavians before mentioned)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This group regularly held meetings at the Menger Hotel Bar of San Antonio. After the Battle of Las Guasimas, the doctor Leonard Wood ceased to be the leader of this group, which presented a president with a bronze miniature of Remington\u2019s<em> Bronco Buster</em>. In their most famous engagement, this group charged up the Kettle and San Juan Hills in Cuba. For ten points, name this volunteer cavalry unit that was led by Teddy Roosevelt during the Spanish American War.", "answer": "<b> Rough Riders</b> (or the<b> 1st</b> United States<b> Volunteer Cavalry</b> Regiment, prompting on partial answers thereof)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This composer depicted the industrialization of the Soviet Union in his ballet<em> The Steel Step</em> and used music from his unperformed ballet<em> Ala i Lolli</em> to write the<em> Scythian Suite</em>. A work by this composer written for an audience of Young Pioneers uses the clarinet to represent a cat, and this composer included the \u201cDance of the Knights\u201d in a Shakespearean ballet. For ten points, name this Soviet composer of the ballet<em> Romeo and Juliet</em> and<em> Peter and the Wolf</em>.", "answer": "Sergei Sergeyevich<b> Prokofiev</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s policy ran on the ideas of \u201cpeace at home, peace in the world,\u201d though his troops almost prompted war with Great Britain in the Chanak crisis. After securing independence, this man was able to replace the Treaty of Sevres with the Treaty of Lausanne. As part of \u201cSix Arrows\u201d ideology, this leader banned the fez. Years after he won at Gallipoli, this leader established a new capital at Ankara. For ten points, name this founder of modern Turkey.", "answer": "Mustafa<b> Kemal Ataturk</b> (accept either underlined portion)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s wounding at the Breymann redoubt is commemorated by the \u201cBoot Monument\u201d in New York. This man was forced to flee on the<em> Vulture</em> after he was implicated by a set of secret plans that were found with John Andre. After Horatio Gates took the credit for this man\u2019s successes at the Battle of Saratoga, this man plotted to surrender West Point to the British. For ten points, name this treasonous American Revolutionary War general.", "answer": "Benedict<b> Arnold</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In the Cutter incident, vaccines of this virus were accidentally tainted with live virus. The inventor of the vaccine for this disease defended his decision to not patent it with the rebuttal \u201cCould you patent the sun?\u201d Wild cases of this disease in 2015 were reported only in Afghanistan and Pakistan. The \u201ciron lung\u201dwas primarily used to assist sufferers of, for ten points, what viral disease whose vaccine was developed by Jonas Salk?", "answer": "<b> polio</b>myelitis", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {}, {"question": "A Polish person of uncertain identity who held this profession is dubbed Gallus Anonymous. Aside from being a monk, a resident of Kiev named Nestor was an early practitioner of this profession. The Byzantine Procopius held this profession, producing a \u201cSecret\u201d book that described the misdeeds of Theodora and Justinian. Herodotus is called the father of, for ten points, what profession that involves chronicling the past?", "answer": "<b> historian</b> (or<b> chronicle</b>r; prompt on answers such as writer or scribe)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In 2014, this country lifted its moratorium on the death penalty after over 140 people were killed in an attack on the Army Public School. This country\u2019s national airline was mocked for sacrificing a goat before a flight, in order to fend off bad luck from a December 2016 plane crash that killed 47 people. For 4 months in 2016, this country imposed a ban on Bollywood films. Nawaz Sharif leads, for ten points, what country whose capital is Islamabad?", "answer": "Islamic Republic of<b> Pakistan</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "When this man took the throne, he killed two of his father\u2019s advisers and his brother Adonijah. This man\u2019s son promised to be harsher to his subjects than this man was, a mistake that led to the division of this man\u2019s kingdom. Earlier, this father of Rehoboam offered a thousand burnt offerings at the Temple he built, for which God gave him wisdom and fabulous wealth. For ten points, name this king of Israel, the son and successor of David.", "answer": "<b> Solomon</b> (accept<b> Shlomo</b>; accept<b> Jedidiah</b>)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "The losing side in this battle lost the commander of its vanguard, Jean le Maingre [MAN-gruh]. The losers were able to successfully raid the baggage train of the victor of this battle, but lost their commander Charles d\u2019Albret and were forced to sign the Treaty of Troyes. A cavalry charge during this battle was bogged down by mud and ran into stakes, leading to massive losses of knights. For ten points, name this decisive victory for English longbowmen during the Hundred Years\u2019 War.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Agincourt</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Shortly before this man\u2019s death, he sent an unsuccessful punitive expedition against the Singhasari kingdom of Java. This man was victorious in the Toluid war against his brother, Ariq Boke, though his attempts to conquer Japan were thwarted by the \u201cdivine wind,\u201d<em> kamikaze</em>. The Italian explorer Marco Polo visited this ruler\u2019s capital of Dadu, located in modern day Beijing. For ten points, name this founder of the Yuan Dynasty in China and grandson of Genghis Khan.", "answer": "<b> Kublai</b> Khan", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This play\u2019s line \u201cI will save you tomorrow... from yourself I will save you\u201d is often omitted because its Act 2, Scene 2 is usually not performed. Liam Neeson starred in a 2002 revival of this play, in which a \u201cpoppet\u201d is created by Mary Warren. After asking for \u201cmore weight,\u201d Giles Corey is crushed to death in this play. John Proctor is hanged at the end of, for ten points, what Red Scare allegory set during the Salem Witch Trials, a play written by Arthur Miller?", "answer": "The<b> Crucible</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Drama"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this city that was besieged twice by the Ottoman Empire as it tried to defeat Austria.", "answer": "<b> Vienna</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>The busiest cantilever bridge in the world connects this city to Howrah. This city\u2019s former Dalhousie Square was renamed B. B. D. Bagh after independence. Located on the Hooghly River, a Home for the Dying was established here by the Missionaries of Charity,</b> <b>led by an (+)</b> <b>Albanian-born nun. This city\u2019s Fort William was the site of a 1756 incident</b> <b>where British prisoners were suffocated in a small room. A (*)</b> \u201cBlack Hole\u201d tragedy took place in, for ten points, what Indian city in the Ganges Delta, the capital of West Bengal and adopted home of Mother Teresa?", "answer": "<b> Kolkata</b> (or<b> Calcutta</b>)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "<b>One block of this city\u2019s Camac Street is paved with wooden blocks. A house on Osage Avenue in this city\u2019s Cobbs Creek section was bombed by the city\u2019s own police force. The (+) 1981 MOVE bombing took place in this city, whose original plan called for five squares, one of which was converted to Logan Circle. A building on this city\u2019s Chestnut Street was the main (*)</b> meeting place for the Second Continental Congress. The Benjamin Franklin Parkway runs through, for ten points, what city, founded by William Penn and home to Independence Hall?", "answer": "<b> Philadelphia</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This subject of one of this artist\u2019s paintings wears a medallion given to him by Alexander the Great while resting his hand on a bust of an ancient poet. This artist\u2019s numerous</b> <b>self-portraits include one etching with his wife, (+)</b> <b>Saskia. He included a young girl in a</b> <b>yellow dress with a chicken hanging from her belt in his portrait of arquebusiers under the command of (*)</b> Frans Banning Cocq. For ten points, name this Dutch artist of<em> The Anatomy Lesson</em> <em>of Dr. Nicolaes Tulp</em> and<em> The Night Watch</em>.", "answer": "<b> Rembrandt</b> van Rijn", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>A contingency plan to defend this structure was drawn up in Operation Sand Flea. A</b> <b>French attempt to build this structure failed when Ferdinand de (+)</b> <b>Lesseps was found</b> <b>to be misappropriating funds. The Darien Scheme tried to build this strcuture, whose construction began in earnest after the (*)</b> Hay-Bunau-Varilla treaty. This structure was returned to the government of Omar Torrijos by Jimmy Carter in 1977. For ten points, name this Central American waterway that links the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans.", "answer": "<b> Panama Canal</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Catherine Cheynel foiled a surprise attack on this city by Charles Emmanuel I of Savoy by pouring soup on the attackers, which is commemorated in</b><em><b> l\u2019Escalade</b></em><b>. Jean-Henri Dunant</b> <b>founded an organization in this city after the Battle of (+)</b> <b>Solferino, and a treaty signed</b> <b>in this city defines the term \u201crefugee.\u201d The Hague Conventions updated a series of treaties signed in this city, home to the International (*)</b> Red Cross. For ten points, name this Swiss city, which names conventions concerning treatment of prisoners of war and non-combatants.", "answer": "<b> Geneva</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This city suffered the \u201cNight of the Black Snow\u201d in 1945. The 20th Air Force frequently</b> <b>attacked this city in Operation Matterhorn. Operation (+)</b> <b>Meetinghouse, which targeted</b> <b>this city for firebombing, was the deadliest single air raid during World War II. A park in (*) </b> Yokoamicho Park commemorates victims of air raids in this city, where the International Military Tribunal for the Far East was held. For ten points, name this Japanese city and capital during World War II.", "answer": "<b> Tokyo</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker!", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>As a beekeeper, this man commissioned Michael Ayrton to create a honeycomb</b> <b>monument. This man conducted the 1955-1958 trans-Antarctic expedition, making</b> <b>him the first person since Robert Scott to reach the (+)</b> <b>South Pole. John Hunt led</b> <b>this man for much of his most famous expedition, in which his team traversed the</b> <b>Khumbu Icefall. This man was knighted for that expedition, unlike (*)</b> Tenzing Norgay, his Sherpa guide. For ten points, name this first person to climb to the summit of Mount Everest.", "answer": "Sir Edmund<b> Hillary</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}], "bonuses": []}